Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1899-1980; 95 boxes (47.5 linear ft.)
  - Main correspondence, ca. 1899-1980; 68 boxes (34 linear ft.)
    - Editions des Deux--Rives-Editions des Gaules, 1948-1951; 21 items. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Editions du Chene, Les (1 of 2), 1944-1948; 78 items. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Editions du Chene, Les (2 of 2), 1948-1960; 83 items. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Editions Francaises Nouvelles--Editions Gallimard, 1945-1962; 16 items. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Editions Masses--Editions Poetry London, 1945-1964; 40 items. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Editorial Seix Barral--Eisiminger, 1945-1966; 32 items. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Ekwensi--Eliot College, 1930-1969; 19 items. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Eliot, Thomas Stearns (T.S. Eliot), 1935-1955; 7 items. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Elkin--Elwell, 1949-1968; 30 items. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Ely, Harry, 1955-1957; 14 items. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Embassy Picture Corp.--Esprit, 1948-1967; 53 items. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Esquire Magazine--European Affairs [publisher], 1945-1969; 38 items. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Evans--Eyster, 1946-1968; 40 items. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Faatz--Fahlnaes, 1950-1966; 14 items. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Fahlneas, Sola Nilsson, 1958-1964; 23 items. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Fain--Familieu, 1947-1968; 24 items. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Fanchette, Jean [editor], 1959-1960; 18 items. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Farber--Fasquelle, 1943-1965; 37 items. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Fassel, Nellie, 1946-1947; 14 items. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Fassett--Fels, 1943-1969; 50 items. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Feltrinelli, Giangiacomo [publisher]--Fenton, Peter, 1947-1966; 29 items. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Fenton, Robert--Ferro, F., 1953-1963; 23 items. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Ferro--Feuerring, 1944-1968; 29 items. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Fex, Jorgen, 1963; 3 items. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Fiandaca, Mariano, 1956-1958; 34 items. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Fichter--Figen, 1946-1968; 12 items. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Figueira de Mello, Andres Boulton, 1964; 6 items. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Figure [publisher]--Fink, Lyman, 1945-1962; 20 items. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Fink, Robert (1 of 3), 1947-1948; 115 items. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Fink, Robert (2 of 3), 1949-1953; 123 items. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Fink, Robert (3 of 3), 1954; 121 items. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Finkelstein--Fitting, 1947-1968; 28 items. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Fitzgerald, Geraldine, 1944-1964; 19 items. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - FitzGibbon--Flagg, 1946-1964; 24 items. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Flak--Flick, 1946-1969; 28 items. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Fluchere, Henri, 1938-1946; 19 items. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Fluck--Forgy, 1946-1968; 35 items. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Forlag Fridtjof-Karla--Form letters, 1944-1958; 16 items. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Forman--Fouere, 1941-1967; 50 items. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Fountaine Library, 1952-1961; 21 items. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Fourteenth Ward, 1954-1955; 26 items. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Fowler, Frances--Fowler, Gene, 1960; 4 items. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Fowlie, Wallace, 1943-1972; 160 items. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Fox--Fraenkel, Daphne, 1958-1966; 8 items. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Fraenkel, Michael, 1933-1956; 35 items. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Fraisier, Jean A., 1944-1954; 13 items. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Fram--Franklin, 1947-1968; 47 items. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Franz, M.H.--French, John D., 1950-1969; 42 items. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - French royalities, 1947-1948; 33 items. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Frendiger--Frimet, 1953-1967; 28 items. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Fritz, Bernardine Szold, 1957-1968; 44 items. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Frohner--Fung, 1947-1968; 55 items. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Fusscas, Louis, 1954-1959; 26 items. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Gabel--Galley Do, 1945-1969; 25 items. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Gallimard, Librarie [publisher], 1947-1960; 25 items. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Gallup--Garde, 1948-1965; 34 items. (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Gardner, Ava, circa 1965; 4 items. (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Gardner--Gay, 1946-1965; 34 items. (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Gaymans, Arnold, 1954-1958; 15 items. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Gaytan--Gedney, 1948-1965; 22 items. (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Geiger--Gellman, 1947-1966; 32 items. (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Gelre, Henk van, 1956-1967; 108 items. (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Gemperle--Georgakas, 1948-1967; 7 items. (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - George, Allan and Marny, 1957-1958; 25 items. (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - George--Gershman, 1949-1968; 12 items. (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Greer--Greiner, 1945-1964; 13 items. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Greiner, S. and Irene, 1951-1957; 23 items. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Grevaul--Grinberg, 1944-1967; 30 items. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Grindea--Group for Film Study, 1946-1968; 20 items. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Grove Press, 1958-1968; 46 items. (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Includes letters from Henry Miller regarding his feelings towards an American printing of the Tropics; also includes discussion of the censorship issues surrounding Lawrence's Lady Chatterly's Lover.
    - GRP Newsletter--Guiglion, 1946-1961; 31 items. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Guilde de Livre [publisher], 1949-1960; 52 items. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Guillumette--Gurbert, 1950-1968; 14 items. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Gurbert, Jean Pigeard de, 1951-1962; 25 items. (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Gutfleisch--Haag, 1950-1968; 24 items. (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Haan, Jacques den, 1945-1949; 33 items. (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Haas--Hajalla, 1945-1979; 17 items. (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Haldeman, Charles, 1957-1965; 22 items. (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Haldeman, Julius E., 1948-1950; 10 items. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Hale--Hall, Kevin, 1946-1966; 19 items. (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - Hall, Ron, 1951-1952; 17 items. (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - Hall, Weeks--Hansen, 1945-1969; 61 items. (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - Hanson--Harder, 1944-1968; 26 items. (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Hardesty, Patti, 1962-1965; 23 items. (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Harding--Harper, Paul, 1946-1968; 37 items. (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Harper's Bazaar [publisher]--Harrington, 1950-1962; 16 items. (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Harris, Dan and Gertrude, 1948-1966; 27 items. (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Gertz, Elmer (1 of 4), 1962; 50 items. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Gertz, Elmer (2 of 4), 1963; 53 items. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Gertz, Elmer (3 of 4), 1964-1966; 77 items. (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Gertz, Elmer (4 of 4), 1967-1969; 21 items. (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Gervais--Giannini, 1947-1969; 22 items. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Gibbs & Phillips, Ltd.--Gilbreath, 1944-1964; 18 items. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Gildart--Ginsbart, 1937-1968; 38 items. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Ginsberg, Allen, circa 1956; 2 items. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Ginsbourg--Giomini, 1936-1958; 12 items. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Giono, Jean, 1945-1948; 15 items. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Giraud--Goff, 1943-1972; 44 items. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Gold--Goll, 1944-1968; 30 items. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Goll, Yvan, 1943-1951; 45 items. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Gomberg--Gomez, 1951-1964; 13 items. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Gonse--Gordon, Robert, 1948-1968; 34 items. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Gordon, William A., 1966-1967; 30 items. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Gore--Gotham Book Mart, 1946-1968; 29 items. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Gotte--Grassi, 1948-1969; 40 items. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Grauer, Ben, 1949-1963; 33 items. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Grauer, Bill (Productions)--Gray, 1948-1968; 16 items. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Graywood--Greenwood Press, 1944-1968; 47 items. (Box 21, Folder 17)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (1 of 8), 1960; 10 items. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (2 of 8), 1961; 17 items. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (3 of 8), 1962; 17 items. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (4 of 8), 1963; 8 items. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (5 of 8), 1964; 17 items. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (6 of 8), 1965; 7 items. (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (7 of 8), 1966; 9 items. (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Gerhardt, Renate (8 of 8), 1967-1968; 6 items. (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Harris--Harvard Law School Forum, 1945-1968; 36 items. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Harvey, Bob, 1952; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Harvey, Dorothy--Hasselbachs Forlag, Steen [publisher], 1946-1960; 15 items. (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Hassoun--Hauglustaine, 1950-1964; 15 items. (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Haupt--Haywood, 1943-1968; 14 items. (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Healey, Giles Greville, 1952-1965; 19 items. (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Healy, Jim--Hearst, 1953-1959; 10 items. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Heath & Company, A. M., 1943-1948; 83 items. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Heath--Heine, 1946-1968; 20 items. (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Heinemann, William, Ltd. [publisher], 1955-1958; 13 items. (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Heinrich, Louis J., 1957-1961; 6 items. (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Heitler--Herschkowitz, 1946-1968; 53 items. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Herschkowitz, Harry, 1944-1948; 1944-1948 items. (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Hersey--Hewitt, 1943-1965; 11 items. (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Hibbard--Higuchi, 1957-1968; 17 items. (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Hiler, Hilaire--Hiler, Hilaire, Jr., 1945-1962; 26 items. (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Hilf--Hinderleider, 1945-1967; 17 items. (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Hindus, Milton, 1947-1949; 12 items. (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Hiner--Hirsch, 1945-1968; 18 items. (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Hirsch, Trygve, 1957-1959; 15 items. (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Hirschburg--Hoffman, 1956-1968; 17 items. (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Hoffman, Agence [publisher; agent] (1 of 2), 1946-1954; 164 items. (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Hoffman, Agence [publisher; agent] (2 of 2), 1955-1962; 164 items. (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Hoffman--Holiday [publisher], 1950-1968; 31 items. (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Hollerer--Holmblad, 1946-1961; 14 items. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Holmes Book Company--Hormell, 1944-1969; 38 items. (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Holmes, Blanca, 1956-1958; 19 items. (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Horn, Andy, 1953-1960; 46 items. (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Hornus, Jean Michel, 1956-1966; 19 items. (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Horoscopes, 1936-1948; 14 items. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Horowitz--Houck, 1956-1960; 15 items. (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Hougland--Hovanitz, 1947-1964; 14 items. (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Howard--Hubi, 1948-1965; 19 items. (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Hubin--Hudson, Martin, Ferrante & Street Attorneys, 1948-1964; 14 items. (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Hudson, Mary--Hutto, 1943-1968; 60 items. (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Huxley, Aldous, 1945-1946; 3 items. (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Hwong--Ing, 1946-1968; 63 items. (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Ingiani--International Festival Clubs, 1955-1966; 38 items. (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Into the Night Life [letters and material], 1947-1948; 48 items. (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Intro Bulletin--Izen, 1952-1968; 21 items. (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Jackermeier--Jacobs, 1954-1968; 22 items. (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Jacobs, Paul and Ruth, 1955-1960; 60 items. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Jacobson--Janson, Hugh, 1943-1968; 47 items. (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Janson, Joseph--Jerrold, 1945-1968; 29 items. (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Jespersen, Josette, 1964-1968; 18 items. (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Joannette--Johnson, Edna, 1949-1968; 17 items. (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Elizabeth Ann Ellsgood McMurray, 1945-1949; 19 items. (Box 26, Folder 6)
      Includes photographs from the Night Life exhibit.
    - Johnson, Frederic--Joisten, 1952-1969; 18 items. (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Jolas, Eugene, 1950; 3 items. (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Jolton--Josephson, 1953-1966; 23 items. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Joses, Douglas G., 1957-1960; ca. 20 items. (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Joski--June, 1958-1967; 7 items. (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Kahana--Kamara, 1952-1968; 27 items. (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Kann--Kaplan, Arnold, 1952-1964; 12 items. (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Kaplan, Edward--Karl, 1945-1967; 23 items. (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Karle--Karmatz, 1955-1966; 18 items. (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Karopoulos--Kataoka, 1948-1965; 20 items. (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Katsimbalis, George C., 1954; 8 items. (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Katz--Kayden, 1954-1967; 24 items. (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Kazan, Elia, 1964-1967; 7 items. (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Kazantzaki--Kelden, 1948-1963; 17 items. (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Keller, Carmelita, 1949-1967; 29 items. (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Kelley--Kerne, 1948-1968; 35 items. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Kerouac, Jack, 1957-1959; 4 items. (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Kerr--Kidder, 1936-1968; 37 items. (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Kidis, John [book dealer], 1950-1960; 92 items. (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Kienholz--Kiser, 1947-1968; 68 items. (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Kitano--Knebel, 1948-1969; 57 items. (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Knight--Koga, James, 1949-1969; 50 items. (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Koga, Tutoma, 1966-1968; 21 items. (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Kohl--Kosmicki, 1947-1968; 28 items. (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Koutsaftis, Sevasty, 1943-1950; 43 items. (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Kozma--Kraus, 1946-1969; 23 items. (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Krauss--Kübler-De Wulf, 1947-1968; 29 items. (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Kubo, S., 1956-1968; 46 items. (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Kucera--Lake Forest College, 1944-1969; 54 items. (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Lake, Carlton--Lake, Jay and Mary, 1944-1958; 30 items. (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Laleure--Lambeth, 1944-1969; 20 items. (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Lambilliotte, Maurice, 1953-1968; 34 items. (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Lamoise--Lancaster, Bob, 1949-1964; 7 items. (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Lancaster, June, 1944-1958; 24 items. (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Lanctôt--Lanowski, 1946-1969; 24 items. (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Lanowski, Zygmund, 1950-1966; 28 items. (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Länsburg--Latour, 1945-1967; 32 items. (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Lauck--Lazzara, 1943-1968; 41 items. (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Le Boterf--Le Roy, 1948-1969; 23 items. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Leahy--Lefort, 1945-1968; 47 items. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Léger, Fernand, 1943-1949; 22 items. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Legg--Leiper, 1939-1968; 24 items. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Leite, George [editor of Circle; director of Daliel's Bookstore], circa 1944-1967; 36 items. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Leites--Les Editions "Le Chichotte", 1947-1968; 25 items. (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Lesdain, Pierre (1 of 3), 1948-1949; 19 items. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Lesdain, Pierre (2 of 3), 1950-1955; 28 items. (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Lesdain, Pierre (3 of 3), 1956-1968; 35 items. (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Lesser--Letch, 1952-1963; 7 items. (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Letchford, Frank, 1952-1961; 53 items. (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Letsche--Levy, 1950-1968; 20 items. (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Lewis--Librairie Plon, 1945-1965; 41 items. (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Library of Congress, 1939-1968; 14 items. (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Libreria Británica--Liebert, 1949-1969; 35 items. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Liebmann, Alfred J. and Edna, 1949-1958; 59 items. (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Liebow, Richard, 1956-1959; 19 items. (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Liefeld--Lippincott, 1944-1969; 51 items. (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Lipton, Lawrence, 1955-1965; 13 items. (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Lisowski--The Literary Review, 1948-1965; 14 items. (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Lithner--Long, 1947-1968; 36 items. (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Longanesi & Co.---Louisiana State University, 1956-1968; 36 items. (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Loujon Press--Louw, 1948-1969; 49 items. (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Lovitz, Gene, 1962-1968; 39 items. (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Lowe--Lublin, 1943-1968; 25 items. (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Lubtchansky--Lyster, 1946-1968; 36 items. (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Maas--Macmillan Company, 1947-1980; 44 items. (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Macy--Madrid, 1946-1967; 31 items. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Madsén, Elmer Page, 1948-1954; 39 items. (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Magalhães--Magnani, Bruna, 1946-1966; 8 items. (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Magnani, Marc de, 1957-1958; 24 items. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Magnum Photos, Inc.--Maigret, 1945-1968; 18 items. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Maillet, Albert, Henri, and Elaine, 1952-1966; 55 items. (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Main Street Book Store--Manning, Charles, 1948-1968; 65 items. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Manning, Hugo, 1945-1969; 43 items. (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Manning, Lilith--Manola, 1952-1960; 24 items. (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Mansfield Book Mart--Margolis, 1947-1968; 31 items. (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Margoshes, Rose and Adam, 1954-1965; 18 items. (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Marguier--Martin, Gale, 1945-1968; 58 items. (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Martin, Helen and Phillip--Martin, Jay, 1953-1966; 18 items. (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Martin, John, 1952-1958; 53 items. (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Martin, Lynn--Masciantonio, 1956-1968; 21 items. (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Mason, Gregory, 1950-1960; 30 items. (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Mason--Mathieu, Bertrand, 1946-1969; 32 items. (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Mathieu, Georges A.--Matisse, 1947-1960; 17 items. (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Matter--Mayer, 1943-1969; 49 items. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Mayfield--Mayoux, 1948-1967; 22 items. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - McCallum--McCullers, 1945-1968; 27 items. (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - McCurtin--McIntyre, Niky, 1947-1969; 38 items. (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - McIntyre, Stephen--Means, 1950-1968; 33 items. (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Mecham, Kathryn, 1949-1966; 64 items. (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Mechem--Mele, Tony, 1948-1967; 37 items. (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Mellard--Merrier, 1947-1966; 25 items. (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Merrild, Knud, 1943-1957; 78 items. (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Merrill--Metzger, 1924-1982; 44 items. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Meulenhoff & Co.--Meyers, 1950-1968; 14 items. (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Michel, Andre--Milford, 1947-1968; 41 items. (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Millard, Henry, 1963-1964; 16 items. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Miller Family Letters, 1899-1962; 44 items. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Miller, Bill--Miller, Charlie, 1954-1967; 13 items. (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Henry to Emil Schelloch, 1933; 1 items. (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Eve, 1960-1962; 7 items. (Box 33, Folder 8)
      With 1 letter by Eve to Lepska Verzeano.
    - Miller, Henry to Eve Miller (1 of 6), circa 1960; 47 items. (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Henry to Eve Miller (2 of 6), 1961; 97 items. (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Miller, Henry to Eve Miller (3 of 6), 1962; 80 items. (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Miller, Henry to Eve Miller (4 of 6), 1963; 58 items. (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Miller, Henry to Eve Miller (5 of 6), 1964; 41 items. (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Miller, Henry to Eve Miller (6 of 6), 1965-1966; 44 items. (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Henry to Hilaire Hiler (1 of 5), 1933-1934; 6 items. (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Miller, Henry to Hilaire Hiler (2 of 5), 1935; 11 items. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Miller, Henry to Hilaire Hiler (3 of 5), 1936-1937; 5 items. (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Henry to Hilaire Hiler (4 of 5), 1941-1961; 10 items. (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Miller, Henry to Hilaire Hiller [copies] (5 of 5), circa 1933-1961; 31 items. (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Miller, Henry to Meyer Hiler, undated; 2 items. (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Henry to Seymour Cohen [?], circa 1926-1935; 8 items. (Box 34, Folder 10)
      Letters written from North Carolina and Paris.
    - Miller, Herbert--Milligan, 1950-1967; 28 items. (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Mills--Miner, 1948-1969; 30 items. (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Mini, Norman, 1949-1965; 20 items. (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Minkoff--Mizuno, 1945-1969; 44 items. (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Moberg--Monat, 1950-1969; 37 items. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Mondadori, Arnoldo [editor], 1946-1964; 41 items. (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Monin--Montserrat, 1946-1966; 41 items. (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Moon--Moore, Robert, 1944-1968; 37 items. (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Moore, Thomas [Henry Miller Literary Society], 1956-1968; 52 items. (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Moorecroft--Morgan, 1951-1968; 19 items. (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Moricand, Conrad (1 of 4), 1938-1945; 20 items. (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Moricand, Conrad (2 of 4), 1946-1947; 50 items. (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Moricand, Conrad (3 of 4), 1948-1949, 1959; 60 items. (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Moricand, Conrad [Miscellaneous] (4 of 4), circa 1908-1954; 22 items. (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Morice-Kerne--Mueller, 1947-1968; 61 items. (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Muench, Gerhart, 1948-1957; 37 items. (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Mühll--Murphy, John, 1948-1968; 37 items. (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Murphy, Louis--Mytkäniemi, 1950-1957; 43 items. (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1962-1966; 5 items. (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Nadeau, Maurice, 1949-1969; 55 items. (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Nader--Naeve, 1950-1968; 15 items. (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Nagle--Narvey, 1952-1967; 17 items. (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Nash, Bob, circa 1954-1968; 33 items. (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Includes 2 original pastels.
    - Nason--Nazarek, 1943-1967; 47 items. (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Neal--Neiman, 1949-1968; 25 items. (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Neiman, Gilbert, 1944; 66 items. (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Nelan--Neville Spearman Limited, 1943-1969; 50 items. (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - New American Library [Victor Weybright], 1952-1958; 74 items. (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - New Directions (01 of 14), 1940-1946; 70 items. (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - New Directions (02 of 14), 1948; 47 items. (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - New Directions (03 of 14), 1949; 30 items. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - New Directions (04 of 14), 1950; 40 items. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - New Directions (05 of 14), 1951; 34 items. (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - New Directions (06 of 14), 1952; 49 items. (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - New Directions (07 of 14), 1953; 12 items. (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - New Directions (08 of 14), 1954; 21 items. (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - New Directions (09 of 14), 1955; 45 items. (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - New Directions (10 of 14), 1956; 74 items. (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - New Directions (11 of 14), 1957; 63 items. (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - New Directions (12 of 14), 1958; 76 items. (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - New Directions (13 of 14), 1959-1960; 104 items. (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - New Directions (14 of 14), 1961-1967; 53 items. (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - New Directions--Contracts, 1940-1959; 11 items. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - New Republic [responses to Miller letter], 1943, 1950; 66 items. (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - New World Publishers--Ney, 1939-1969; 36 items. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Niarcho--Nikhilananda, 1941-1968; 41 items. (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Nin, Anaïs, 1933, 1947-1948, 1968; 8 items. (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Nishino-Norske, 1948-1968; 27 items. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Norman-Nyman, 1940-1968; 49 items. (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Nyes, Marguerite, 1950-1961; 67 items. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Nyst-Oaks, 1953-1969; 13 items. (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Obelisk Press [Tropic of Cancer contract], 1937-1940; 18 items. (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Ober-Okumura, 1945-1969; 49 items. (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Olay, Lionel, 1957-1963; 15 items. (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Oldfield, Claude Houghton, 1942-1959; 61 items. (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - O'Leary-Olsen, 1940-1965; 22 items. (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Olshausen, George [attorney] (1 of 3), 1950-1954; 79 items. (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Olshausen, George [attorney] (2 of 3), 1949-1950; 38 items. (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Olshausen, George [attorney] (3 of 3), 1950-1953; 49 items. (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Olympia Press [publisher]--O'Malley, 1946-1959, 1968; 53 items. (Box 39, Folder 14)